Guide to the Picture File, 1600s-1979 and undated, bulk 1814-1950
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Oversize Materials Not in Main Collection
  - Geographic Series
    - Germany (Box OV1)
      - Coburg, undated, (lithograph)
      - [Dresden] "Das Alte Rathhaus...," 1708, (lithograph)
      - [Dresden] "Das Königliche Schloss...," 1756, (lithograph)
      - [Dresden] "Der Neumarkt Um Das Jahr 1750," 1750, (lithograph)
      - [Frankfurt] "Die Franckfurther Brücke über den Maÿn...," undated, (lithograph)
      - [Ingolstadt] "Ingolstadt soA: 1632 von dem Konige aus Schweden...," undated, (lithograph)
      - [Königliche] "Grofses Concert der Königl. Hofkapelle...," 1812 May 24, (lithograph)
      - [Metz] "Metz -- Eine von denen Dreÿen...," undated, (lithograph)
      - [Regensburg] "Die Donaw Brück zu Regenspurg," undated, (lithograph)
      - [Rotenberg] "Der Rothe-Berg Beÿ 4. Stund von Nürmberg gelegen," undated, (lithograph)
      - [Ulm] "Ulm gegen Sud Osten," undated, (lithograph)
    - Kentucky
      - "City of Louisville," 1872, (color engraving) (Box OV1)
    - Louisiana
      - "New Orleans," 1800s, (color engraving) (Box OV1)
      - "New Orleans," 1800s, (color engraving)
    - Maryland
      - [Baltimore] Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1900s, (card photograph) (Box OV1)
      - "City of Baltimore," 1800s, (color engraving)
      - [Frederick] Mt. Olivet Cemetery, undated, (card photograph)
    - New Hampshire
      - Portsmouth, undated, (engraving) (Box OV1)
    - North Carolina
      - [Bath] "Souvenir Calender, Ye Old Bath Town, 1705-1905," circa 1906, (calendar) (Box OV1)
        Calendar of 29 black-and-white photographic illustrations.
      - [Currituck County] Poplar Branch Township, 1900s, (6 card photographs)
      - [Durham] Bennett House, 1876 and undated, (2 lithographs) (Box OV2)
        One lithograph is glossy.
      - [Durham] Bennett Place, 1974 Sept. 5, (color illustration)
        Includes a description of the Bennett House's history.
      - [Durham] Commonwealth Cotton Mill Employees, circa 1896, (2 card photographs)
      - [Durham] Duke Memorial Methodist Church. Men's Bible Class taught by Dr. Hersey Evenette Spence(?), 1900s, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] Duke, W. and Sons' Second Durham factory, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] Duke, W. and Son's second Durham factory (1885) with a view of "Fairview" and..., undated, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] Durham County Courthouse, undated, (card photograph)
        Photograph is tinted.
      - [Durham] Durham Female Seminary, 1800s, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] "Fairview," house of Washington Duke, and the first tobacco factory..., undated, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] Grade School 1889, 1889, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] "Holy City" Choir, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] Poe, Clarence Talton, Sr. Homes and family, 1900s and undated, (1 card photograph and 1 black-and-white photograph)
      - [Durham] Southern Conservatory of Music, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Durham] W. Duke and Son's Co. Factory, 1901 Sept. 14-15, (card photograph)
        The factory is draped in mourning for the assassinated President McKinley.
      - [Durham] West Chapel Hill Street, 1925 Oct. 1, (black-and-white photograph)
      - "Hickory Nut Falls N.C.," 1858, (color lithograph)
      - "Mitchell's Falls," 1857, (color lithograph)
      - "North Carolina Senators and Representatives in the Confederate Congress, 1861-1865," 1800s, (black-and-white photograph)
      - Ratification of the Constitution
      - Rowan County, 1763
      - [Salem] "Church and Inspectors House," undated, (black-and-white illustration)
      - [Salem] "Young Ladies Seminary," undated, (black-and-white illustration)
    - Russia
      - "Russisches Blockaus...," undated, (color illustration) (Box OV2)
    - Tennessee
      - [Anderson] "Military Post Anderson, Tenn.," 1800s, (color lithograph) (Box OV2)
      - [Cowan] "View of Military Post Cowan, Tennessee.," 1800s, (color lithograph)
    - Virginia
      - "Monticello -- Home of Thomas Jefferson," 1900s, (color illustration) (Box OV2)
      - "Richmond from the James," 1800s, (color engraving)
      - [Richmond] "The White House of the Confederacy, Richmond, Va.," undated, (black-and-white illustration)
      - [Westmoreland] "Stratford, The Birthplace of Gen. Robert E. Lee, Westmoreland Co., Va.," undated, (2 black-and-white illustrations)
        The smaller illustration is a photogravure, a special method of photo-reproduction, of the larger original. The large original illustration has a negative available.
    - West Virginia
      - "Bird's Eye View of Philippi, West Virginia, 1897," undated, (color illustration) (Box OV2)
      - "Harper's Ferry by Moonlight," 1874, (color engraving)
    - Western photographs
  - Geographic Series
    - South Carolina
      - [Charleston] S.C. Interstate and West Indian Exposition, 1901-1902, (6 card photographs) (Box OV2)
      - [Charleston] S.C. Interstate and West Indian Exposition, 1901-1902, (7 card photographs)
      - [Charleston] Citadel, undated, (card photograph)
        From "Lowdermilk's Book Store, Washington D.C. 1966."
      - [Charleston] College of Charleston, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Charleston] Female Orphan Asylum, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Charleston] Hiberman Society Hall, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Charleston] Mills House, undated, (card photograph)
      - [Charleston Ruins], undated, (card photograph)
      - [Charleston] Ruins in Charleston, undated, (card photograph)
    - Georgia
      - [Savannah] The Old Pirate House, undated, (black-and-white photograph) (Box OV3)
    - Tennessee
      - Chattanooga, 1865, (3 black-and-white photographs) (Box OV3)
  - Military
    - Spanish-American War
      - "The Rescue of Gilmore," circa 1899, (card photograph) (Box OV3)
    - Civil War
      - "After the Battle. 'Bloody Lane' Antietam," 1889 Aug. 28, (card photograph) (Box OV3)
        Copy of a painting by Capt. James Hope.
      - "Bombardment of Fort Hatteras, North Carolina, August 29th 1861...," undated, (color lithograph)
      - "Camp of the 37th Mass. Vol's. Near Brandy Station Va.," 1800s, (lithograph)
      - "Camp Chesebrough, Baltimore, Md. -- 1st Reg. Connecticut Cavalry," 1863, (color lithograph)
      - "Camp Oliver 25th Mass. V. Infantry, New Berne, N.C. 1862," undated, (color lithograph)
      - "Campbell U.S. Genl. Hospital, Washington, D.C.," 1864, (color lithograph)
      - "Carver Barracks, Washington D.C.," 1864, (color lithograph)
      - "The Civil War in America: Advanced Post of General Blenker's Division...," 1862 Jan. 18, (clipping)
      - "Cliffburne Hospital, Washington D.C.," 1862, (color lithograph)
      - "Come and Join Us Brothers," 1863, (color lithograph)
        Includes a photocopy of the original image.
      - "Grand Gulf City. Return of the 4th Wis. and 6th Mich. Volunteers...," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "In Memoriam," 1867, (engraving)
      - "President Jefferson Davis, His Ministers and Escort Passing...," 1800s, (black-and-white illustration)
        From "The Confederate Soldier in the Civil War," Ed. by Ben La Bree. Published at Louisville, Ky., 1895.
      - "Pugna Pro Patria," 1800s, (engraving)
      - "Storming of Fort Fisher," undated, (color illustration)
      - "Surrender of Port Hudson, La. July 8th 1863," undated, (color lithograph)
      - "Willard Guard, Company G.," 1800s, (lithograph)
      - "The Assassination of President Lincoln," 1865, (lithograph)
        From the Currier and Ives Collection.
      - "The Battle of Antietam, MD. Sept. 17th 1862," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "The Battle of Chickamauga, Geo.," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Battle of Corinth, Miss. Oct. 4th 1862," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Battle of Corinth, Miss. Oct. 4th 1862," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Battle of New Bern, N.C. March 14th 1862," 1862, (color lithograph)
      - "The Battle of Petersburg Va. April 2nd 1865," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "The Battle of the Wilderness Va. May 5th and 6th 1864," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "The Blockade on the 'Connecticut Plan,'" 1862, (black-and-white illustration)
      - "Bombardment of Fort Pulaski, Cockspur Island, Geo....," 1862, (color lithograph)
      - "The Death of the Just," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "The Death of the Sinner," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Edward Everett, Our Next Vice President," [1860], (color lithograph)
        From the Currier and Ives Collection. Contains possibly authentic signature.
      - "Freedom to the Slaves," 1800s, (lithograph)
      - "General Stoneman's Great Cavalry Raid, May 1863," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Glorious Charge of Hancock's Division 2nd of the Army of the Potomac," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Hon. John Bell, 'Our Next President,'" 1860, (color lithograph)
      - "The Lake of the Dismal Swamp," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Lieut. Gen. N. B. Forrest," 1800s, (engraving)
      - "Major-Genl. Franz Sigel, the Hero of the West," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Old Blandford Church," 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - "Satterlee U.S.A. General Hospital, West Philadelphia," 1864, (color lithograph)
      - "Surrender of Port Hudson, La. July 8th 1863," 1863, (color lithograph)
  - Ships
    - "The Confederate Sloop-of-War Sumter Capturing Two Federal Merchantmen...," 1862 Feb. 1, (clipping) (Box OV3)
  - Art
    - "Married," 1800s, (color lithograph) (Box OV3)
  - People
    - A-C
      - Burkett, Norman, 1948, (black-and-white illustration) (Box OV4)
      - Brown, John, 1800s, (engraving)
      - Brown, Joseph E., 1800s, (black-and-white photographic illustration)
      - Burgwin, John, 1800s, (card photograph)
      - Volunteers of "Lazarus Institute"..., 1900s, (card photograph)
        From the James Cannon Jr. Papers.
      - Carter, Jimmy, et al., 1979 Oct. 17, (card photograph)
        Picture for Terry Sanford, with a signed note from Charlie Rose.
      - Cannon, James Jr., et al., 1900s, (card photograph)
      - Cotten, Robert R., undated, (card photograph)
      - Cherry, R. Gregg, 1949 Jan. 1, (black-and-white photographic illustration)
        Includes personal note and signature of NC Gov. R. Gregg Cherry.
      - Cobb, Howell, 1800s, (engraving)
    - D-G
      - Davis, Jefferson -- Arriving in the Field..., circa 1861, (lithograph) (Box OV4)
        Includes a note describing this image as an early Confederate imprint by Royler and Ludwig.
      - Dewey, George, 1915, (card photograph)
        Includes dedication and signature of George Dewey.
      - Durham High School, class of 1905, 1905, (card photograph)
      - Eng and Chang - Siamese Twins, 1839, (lithograph)
      - Few, Benjamin Franklin, 1800s, (2 black-and-white photographic illustrations)
      - George III, King of Great Britain, undated, (2 engravings)
      - George II, undated, (2 engravings)
      - Gibbons, James Cardinal, undated, (engraving)
      - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang, 1828, (engraving)
      - Lieut. Gen. Grant, Ulysses S., 1800s, (engraving)
      - Gregg, William, undated, (black-and-white photograph)
    - H-J
      - Harding, Warren Gameliel, 1920, (black-and-white photographic illustration) (Box OV4)
      - Hayes, Hubert Harrison, 1900s, (3 card photographs)
      - Hoey, Clyde Roark, 1900s, (card photograph)
        Includes Hoey's signature.
      - Hoke, Michael, 1800s, (sketch)
      - Hope, Leslie Town (Bob), 1949, (black-and-white photograph)
        Includes dedication and signature of Bob Hope.
      - Howley, William, Bishop of London, 1886, (engraving)
      - Johnson, Richard Menton, 1800s, (lithograph)
      - Johnston, Joseph E., 1800s, (lithograph)
        From "The Confederate Soldier in the Civil War."
    - L-P
      - "Recumbent Figure of General R. E. Lee," 1875, (card photograph) (Box OV4)
      - Robert E. Lee, 1800s, (engraving)
      - Gen. R. E. Lee and Staff, 1866, (card photograph)
      - Lewell-McDonald Family--chart, undated
      - Lincoln, Abe, 1964-1970, Lloyd Ostendorf, artist, (4 black-and-white illustrations)
        From the Lincoln Memorial University Collection.
      - Lincoln, A., 1860, (black-and-white photographic illustration)
      - Lincoln, Abraham, 1860, Alexander Hesler, photographer, (black-and-white photograph)
        Includes descriptive note (photocopy).
      - Longstreet, James, Lieut. Gen., 1800s, (lithograph)
      - Lumpkin, Wilson, 1838, (lithograph)
      - Myers, Rosa Mae (Warren), undated, (card photograph)
      - Oaksmith, Appleton, 1800s, (black-and-white photograph)
      - Parrish, Rosa (Bryan), Mrs. Edward James, undated, (card photograph)
      - Perceval, Spencer, undated, (engraving)
      - Percey, William, Rev., 1772 Sept. 17 and 1774 July 5, (2 engravings)
      - Pickens, Marshall Ivey, 1900s, (black-and-white photograph)
        Includes signature of Pickens.
      - Purnell, Thomas R., 1900s, (card photograph)
    - Negroes (African Americans)
      - "The Merry Slave," 1857, (color engraving) (Box OV4)
      - A Posed Photograph of two Negroes Picking Cotton, 1892, (black-and-white photograph)
    - P
      - [Powers, James Thomas], undated, (3 card photographs, 1 handbill and 6 black-and-white photographic illustrations)
    - Q-Z
      - Revels, H. R. - Sen. from Miss., 1800s, (engraving) (Box OV4)
      - Reynolds, William Neal, 1900s, (card photograph)
      - Rogers, Samuel, 1822, Aug. 16, (engraving)
      - Romaine, William, Rev., undated, (engraving)
      - Roosevelt and Lincoln, 1905, (engraving)
      - Russell, Lord John, First Earl Russell, 1800s, (engraving)
      - Ritchie, Thomas, 1800s, (engraving)
      - Sargent, D. A., undated, (card photograph)
        Transferred from the Wilbur Wade Card Papers.
      - "Sir Walter Scott Bart.", 1833 Sept., (engraving)
      - Simpson, W. M., 1800s, (card photograph)
      - South Carolina Legislature (Radical Members), 1800s, (card photograph)
      - Southgate, James Haywood, 1900s, (black-and-white photographic illustration)
      - Wellesley, Arthur [Duke of Wellington], 1836, (engraving)
      - "Old Orthodox" (John Wesley), 1777, Oct. 9, (engraving)
      - Wesley, John -- Rev., 1800s, (color lithograph)
      - Yohannan, Mar., Bishop of Ooroomiah, 1842, (lithograph)
  - Cartoons
    - "A Pedlar and his Pack or the Desperate Effort, an Overbalance," circa 1826, (political cartoon, color) (Box OV5)
      Depicts John Quincy Adams, Henry Clay, Daniel Webster carrying coffins; possibly in reference to Panama mission of 1826.
  - Geographic Series
    - North Carolina (Box OV5)
      - "Washington Duke's First Factory, Duke Homestead," circa 1870s, (black-and-white photograph, albumen print)
  - Socialist Party Records Series
    - Labor miscellany, 1958-1964 (Box OV5)
    - People
      - "1st Unity Convention, Indianapolis 1901," 1901, (card photograph) (Box OV5)
      - Berger, Victor Louis, circa 1945 Mar. 2, (black-and-white photograph)
      - "A Bunch of Progressive Women," undated, (card photograph)
      - "Delegates to the 1st National Convention...," 1904 May, (card photograph)
      - "Delegates to the National Convention of the Socialist Party," 1908 May, (black-and-white photographic illustration)
      - Wilson, Harold, 1964 May, (card photograph)
        Signed by Harold Wilson.
      - Group of Socialists, 1911, (card photograph)
      - "Meeting of Presidential and Vice Presidential...," 1920 Oct. 2, (card photograph)
        This is actually a pair of photographs attached to a single card. Negative available.
      - "Members of State Legislatures...," 1913, (card photograph)
      - "National Nominating Convention...," 1900, (card photograph)
  - Cartoons
    - Cartoon Collection
      - American Tobacco Co. Nos. 112-118, undated, (6 color illustrations and 6 slides) (Box OV5)
        The slides and six illustrations are copies of the items in the following entry.
      - American Tobacco Co. Nos. 112-118, undated, (6 color illustrations)
        These are the original illustrations, copied in the previous entry.
        These cartoons are nos. 112-118 in the Cartoon Collection.
      - "The Beauties of Boswell," 1942, Rawlandson, Thomas cartoonist, (album)
        20th century reproductions of nine original color cartoons printed in 1786. Includes an introduction.
      - Benjamin Franklin Butler in the Civil War, 1861 and circa 1860s, (6 clippings and 1 engraving)
        These cartoons are nos. 18-24 in the Cartoon Collection.
      - [Civil war political cartoons], 1861-1865, (52 engravings)
        Published in "Fun Magazine," London.
        These cartoons are nos. 37-89 in the cartoon collection.
      - Jefferson Davis, 1861, 1863, 1865 and circa 1860s, (5 engravings, 5 card photographs, 7 black-and-white illustrations, 2 color illustrations and 3 pamphlets
        These cartoons are nos. 90-107 in the Cartoon Collection.
      - Secession and the Civil War, 1800s and 1770, (14 engravings and 1 color engraving)
        These cartoons are nos. 25-36 in the Cartoon Collection.
      - U.S. Politics 1831-1841, 1831-circa 1841, (15 engravings and 2 color engravings)
        These cartoons are nos. 1-17 in the Cartoon Collection.
  - Geographic Series
    - South Carolina
      - Charleston, S.C., 1800s, (color lithograph) (Box OV5)
    - South Dakota
      - Mount Rushmore Memorial, circa 1938, (6 black-and-white photographs) (Box OV6)
        Two of these photographs are from the Harry A. Slattery Papers.
  - African American Caricatures (from Currier and Ives)
    - Darktown Lawn Party: A Bully Time (Box OV6)
    - Darktown Lawn Party: Music in the Air
    - Draw Poker: Getting Em Lively
    - Draw Poker: Layin for Em Sharp
    - Bustin in the Pool
    - Two to Go
    - Got Em Both
    - Great Oyster Eating Match
    - A Fair Start
    - The Result in Doubt
    - On His Style
    - Off His Nut
  - Military
    - Revolutionary War (Box OV6)
      - "View of the West Bank of the Hudson's River...," 1789, (1 black-and-white photograph and 1 lithograph)
  - Ships
    - Connecticut, U.S.S., 1904-1906, (17 black-and-white photographs) (Box OV6)
  - Geographic Series
    - Arkansas
      - "Perspective Map of Van Buren, Arkansas," 1888, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
    - Brazil
      - "Bella vista a esquarda," undated, (black-and-white photograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Landscape, aerial view.
    - California
      - "Los Angeles, Los Angeles county, Cal. 1857," 1959, (black-and-white illustrations) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Re-published by the California Historical Society.
    - Georgia
      - "Old Pirates House, East Broad and Wright Streets, Savannah GA," 1946, (black-and-white watercolor (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Original painting by Harriet Cann.
    - Kentucky
      - "The Homestead of Henry Clay," 1853, (black-and-white engraving) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Front view of house, Negative attached.
    - Maryland
      - "Annapolis, Capital of the State," 1838, (black-and-white lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Harbor view
      - "Panoramic View of Skyline of Baltimore, MD," undated, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Long folding postcard, view from body of water.
    - New York
      - "Great International Naval Review," 1893, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Colorful, stylized illustration of boats.
    - North Carolina
      - East Durham Methodist Episcopal Church, 1929, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Appears to be a concept drawing by architect.
      - [Durham] High School Class of 1908, (black-and-white photo) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - New Bern, Harbor, 1864, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - [Raleigh] Gen. Assembly House of Rep., 1915, (black-and-white photo) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Photos with corresponding names of each representative.
      - [Roanoke], ( (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Southwest View of Salem," undated, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
    - Pennsylvania
      - "100th Anniversary of the Independence of the United States," 1876, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Poster showing centennial exhibition buildings.
    - Tennessee
      - Johnson City, undated, (black-and-white illustrations) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Group of printed photos of Johnson city from 1890, relates to Daughters of the American Revolution conference, 1923.
    - Virginia
      - "Battle of Yorktown," undated, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Photo of painting.
      - "Washington's Sepulchre, Mt. Vernon," undated, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - Roanoke, Red Sulphur Springs, 1857, (color illustration)
    - West Virginia
      - "Parkersburg, WV," 1899, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Bird's eye perspective.
      - "Sistersville, WV" 1896, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "St. Mary's, WV" 1899, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
  - Subjects Series
    - Tobacco
      - "Earliest Known Illustration showing an American Tobacco Factory" 1667-1671, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Translation of French original. Depicts Native American camp.
      - "Dinner of the American Tobacco Co. Hotel," 1913, (black-and-white photo) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Group photo at dinner.
    - Mexican War
      - "Valley towards Saltillo, with the rear guard and wagon train of the US army coming into the castle after its capitulation," 1847, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "View of Monterey from Independence Hill, near the Bishop's palace, with the village of Guadaloupe and Sierra Silla, or Saddle Mountain, in the distance," 1847, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Sketch of the Encampment of the US Army at Corpus Christi," 1847, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Monterey, as seen from a house top on the east side of the main plaza, after the capture of the city by US forces," 1847, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Heights of Monterey, with the 22 division, commanded by General Worth, moving into position under the guns of the enemy," 1847, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
    - Civil War
      - "German Artillery Near Washington," 1861, (black-and-white photo) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Assault on Fort Sanders," 1891, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
        Kurz and Allison
      - "Battle of Cedar Creek," 1890, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Corinth," 1891, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Champion Hill," 1887, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Fort Donelson," 1887, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Franklin," 1891, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Lookout Mountain," 1889, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Oluster, Florida," 1894, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Resaca," 1889, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Williamsburg," 1893, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Battle of Wilson Creek," 1893, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Capture of Fort Fisher," 1890, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Fort Pillow Massacre," 1892, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Siege of Vicksburg," 1888, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)
      - "Storming of Fort Wagner," 1890, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:I:1)